#### 

# Saeed Mirshekari

# SUMMARY

Data Scientist with PhD in Astrophysics with 2 years post doctoral experience in academia (Data Analysis team of LIGO) and 3+ years of work experience in industry. 10+ years of successful research experience in both theoretical and computational physics. Strong problem–solving and leadership skills. Looking for new opportunities towards leading small technical, data-science teams.

Advanced programming proficiency. Certified and experienced in Machine Learning and Deep Learning. Self-motivated and fast-learner. Skilled in collaborations, process improvement, with the ability to translate deep technical ideas and new concepts across all organizational levels. Strong skills in prioritizing, organizing, and time management with strong verbal and written communication skills.

## Highlights

- 5+ years work experience in Data Analysis
- 20+ presentations in international conferences
- 10+ awarded research and travel grants
- 50+ publications in top science journals
- 10+ MOOCs in cutting edge ML & DL
- Team lead experience

# Work Experience

#### FULL TIME EMPLOYMENT

- o Bayer (Monsanto), St. Louis, MO [Data Scientist] (2017–Present)
- Aclara Technologies, St. Louis, MO [Data Scientist] (2016–2017)
- o ICTP-SAIFR, São Paulo, Brazil [Postdoctoral Research Fellow] (2013–2015)
- Washington University in St. Louis, MO [Research Assistant] (2009–2013)

#### VISITING RESEARCH SCHOLAR

- Caltech Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA (Mar 2015)
- University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, Milwaukee, WI (Jan-Feb 2014 & Sep 2014)
- o University of Florida, Gainesville, FL (Nov 2012 to Aug 2013)
- o Institut d'Astrophysique de Paris, Paris (July-Sep 2012)
- o MIT Kavli Institute, Boston, MA (Mar 2011)

### EDUCATION

- o Ph.D. in Physics, Washington University in St. Louis, MO (2013)
- M.Sc. in Physics, University of Tehran, Iran (2008)
- B.Sc. in Physics, University of Tehran, Iran (2005)

## Computer Skills and Languages

- $\circ\,$  Programming languages including  $\mathbf{Python},\,\mathbf{R},\,\mathbf{MATLAB},\,\mathbf{C},\,\mathrm{and}$  ,  $\mathbf{Bash}$  [5+ years]
- Analytical and computational tools including Maple and Mathematica [3+ years]
- Web-based analytical tools including **RShiny** and **AzureML** [1+ years]
- Distributed computing via **HTCondor**
- Version control systems including GIT, CVS, and TSF
- Full fluency in English and Persian, basic skills in Arabic and Portuguese

#### CERTIFICATES IN DATA SCIENCE

- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera.
   [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Laurence Moroney]
- 2019 Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Laurence Moroney]
- 2019 **Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow**, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Laurence Moroney]
- 2019 **Sequences, Time Series and Prediction**, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Laurence Moroney]
- 2018 **Neural Networks and Deep Learning**, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2018 Improving Deep Neural Networks, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2018 **Structuring Machine Learning Projects**, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2018 **Convolutional Neural Networks**, Offered by deeplearning.ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2018 **Sequence Models**, Offered by deeplearning ai via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2015 **Data Science and Machine Learning Essentials**, Offered by Microsoft via edX. [A 5-week online course; Instructors: Steve Elston and Cynthia Rudin]
- 2015 **Statistical Learning**, Offered by Stanford University via Dataschool.io. [A 10-week online course; Instructors: Trevor Hastie and Robert Tibshirani]
- 2014 **Machine Learning**, Offered by Stanford University via Coursera. [A 10-week online course; Grade:100%, Instructor: Andrew Ng]
- 2014 R Programing, Offered by Johns Hopkins University via Coursera.

  [A 4-week online course; Grade:100% with Distinction, Instructors: Roger Peng, Jeff Leek, B. Caffo]
- 2014 **The Data Scientists Toolbox**, Offered by Johns Hopkins University via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructors: Roger Peng, Jeff Leek, Brian Caffo]
- 2014 **Getting and Cleaning Data**, Offered by Johns Hopkins University via Coursera. [A 4-week online course; Instructors: Roger Peng, Jeff Leek, Brian Caffo]

#### AWARDS

2016 Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics, for the detection of gravitational waves. The Breakthrough Prize recognizes the world's top scientists. Each prize is \$3 million and presented in the fields of Life Sciences (up to five per year), Fundamental Physics (up to one per year) and Mathematics (up to one per year).

A Special Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics was awarded to 1015 scientists and engineers contributing to the detection of gravitational waves announced in February of 2016.

#### VOLUNTARY ACTIVITIES

2019 Data Science Teacher, CoderGirl.

CoderGirl is LaunchCode's education program designed to engage and educate women in the technology community in St. Louis. Originally created as a meetup by women to lift up other women in tech, over time CoderGirl has grown into a full-fledged education job prep program, but our mission remains the same. We welcome everyone who identifies as female into our supportive learning community.

The program begins with a 24-week or 45-week specialized track designed to equip CoderGirls with technical skills and job-readiness skills, leading up to our apprenticeship job program. CoderGirl provides a space for women of all skill levels to learn to code in a supportive community of like-minded individuals.